Guide to the Robert A. Hill Collection, 1890-2014 RL.10993
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Project Administration (PA), 1977-2013 and undated; 4; 25 boxes
  - Correspondence, 1
    - Harvard - DuBois Institute, 1980-1981 (Box PA19)
    - Caribbean - contributor information, 1998-2000 (Box PA20)
    - Contributors, 1998-1999 (Box PA20)
    - Caribbean Series - contributing scholars contracts, 2009-2010; 2 folders (Box PA20)
    - Independent consult agreements, 1985-1986 (Box PA20)
    - Caribbean Series - contributing scholars mailing addresses, 2002-2009 (Box PA20)
    - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box PA20)
    - Gates, Henry Louis, Jr., 2001 Apr 1 (Box PA20)
    - Lee, Paul, 2003 (Box PA20)
    - Library of Congress, 1971-1983 (Box PA20)
    - African Series - Sadler, Katherine, 1992 (Box PA20)
    - Barnes, Isaac Edmestone, 1996, 2000 (Box PA20)
    - Brown, Katie - Cleveland, Ohio, undated (Box PA20)
    - H-Net, 2002 Jun-Sep (Box PA20)
    - Jamaica - book launch, 1991-1992 (Box PA20)
    - Royal Archives, Hinchcliffe, 2000 (Box PA20)
    - Columbia Archives, 1999 (Box PA20)
    - Foreign and Commonwealth Office, 1992-1998 (Box PA20)
    - National Archives of Zimbabwe, 1996-2000 (Box PA20)
    - Marcus Garvey and UNIA Papers Project, 1992-1993 (Box PA20)
    - Zimbabwe, 1992-1996 (Box PA20)
    - Massaquoi, Momolu, undated (Box PA20)
    - Archives and libraries - UK and Europe, 1993-1997 (Box PA20)
    - Phillips, J.E.T. (Tracy) - miscellaneous inquiries, 2002 Aug (Box PA20)
    - Caribbean, 1995-1998 (Box PA20)
    - South African Library, 1992-1996 (Box PA20)
    - South Africa - Cape Archives, University of Cape Town, 1993-1996 (Box PA20)
    - South Africa - Other Archives and Libraries, 1992-1996 (Box PA20)
    - Malawi, 1992-1997 (Box PA20)
    - Ghana, 1992, 1996 (Box PA20)
    - Nigeria, 1992-1996 (Box PA20)
    - Tanzania, 1995-1996 (Box PA20)
    - African Series - scholars, 1986 Sep-Dec; 2 folders (Box PA20)
    - Bundesarchiv Germany, 2002 (Box PA20)
    - Vatican Secret Archives, 2001 (Box PA20)
    - Pagano, Sergio and Vatican Secret Archives, 2000-2001 (Box PA20)
    - Blouin, Francis, Jr., 2001 (Box PA20)
    - England - House of Commons Library, 1973-1974, 1980 (Box PA20)
    - England - Home Office, 1977 (Box PA20)
    - Wickham, John - Barbados, 1975-1976 (Box PA20)
    - Brazil, 1980-1983 (Box PA20)
    - University of East Anglia - English universities, 1975 (Box PA20)
    - US Embassy in England, 1973 (Box PA20)
    - Northern Ireland, 1981, 1992 (Box PA20)
    - Israel, 1973 (Box PA20)
    - Jamaica - universities and schools, 1970, 1984-1988 (Box PA20)
    - Philippines, 1982 (Box PA20)
    - Puerto Rico, 1975-1979 (Box PA20)
    - Aptheker, Herbert, 1978-1984 (Box PA20)
    - South Africa - Saunders, Christopher, 1973-1986 (Box PA20)
    - St. Louis - research, 1981 (Box PA20)
    - Oklahoma, 1979-1980 (Box PA20)
    - Oregon, 1973-1987; 2 folders (Box PA20)
    - Pennsylvania government, 1978-1983 (Box PA20)
    - Kansas, 1978-1985 (Box PA20)
    - Kentucky, 1976-1984 (Box PA20)
    - North Carolina - business, media, 1981-1984 (Box PA20)
    - Idaho, 1985-1987 (Box PA20)
    - Illinois State government, 1972-1976 (Box PA20)
    - India, 1973, 1982 (Box PA20)
    - Iowa, 1974-1985 (Box PA20)
    - West Virginia, 1981-1984 (Box PA20)
    - Washington State, 1971, 1978-1987 (Box PA20)
    - USICA - DC, 1979 (Box PA20)
    - Washington DC - companies, businesses, railroads, 1979-1984 (Box PA20)
    - Tennessee - government, 1981 (Box PA20)
    - Texas - libraries, archives, government, 1971-1985 (Box PA20)
    - Institute of Commonwealth Studies and University of London, Oxford University, 1973-1979, 1985-1986 (Box PA20)
    - Malawi, undated (Box PA21)
    - Kaduna, Nigeria, undated (Box PA21)
    - Enubu, Nigeria, undated (Box PA21)
    - Clifford, Hugh, from Tidrick, K., undated (Box PA21)
    - Lamina, Epegory, Nigeria, 1969-1970 (Box PA21)
    - Ibadan, Nigeria, undated (Box PA21)
    - DuBois in Sierra Leone, 1925 (Box PA21)
    - Research queries: U.S. libraries and archives, 1991-1997 (Box PA21)
    - Garvey Papers and contributors, external readers, 1985-1997 (Box PA21)
    - Connelly, Tim - NHPRC, 1992-1998 (Box PA21)
    - Research queries - individuals, 1992-1998 (Box PA21)
    - Archives of the Episcopal Church, 1999 Feb (Box PA21)
    - African World, London, 1921 (Box PA21)
    - Harvard University, Massachusetts, 1973-1992 (Box PA21)
    - Archives - DEFAP, 1992 (Box PA21)
    - Kenya, Uganda, 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Namibia, 1992-1996 (Box PA21)
    - MEP-2 copyright permission, 2000-2001 (Box PA21)
    - Clegg, Thomas, 1995 (Box PA21)
    - Work for MEPP-2, undated (Box PA21)
    - Digitalization meetings, 1998-2000 (Box PA21)
    - Frazier, E. Franklin - The DuBois Program in the Present Crisis, undated (Box PA21)
    - Copyright information, 1976-1978 (Box PA21)
    - Bob Edgar documents, 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Archives Africaines, Brussels (AA), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Archives of the Department of State, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Monrovia, Liberia (ADSL), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Federal Archives and Record Center, East Point, Georgia (AFRC), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Archives de Ministere des Affaires Etrangeres (AMAE), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Arquivo de Ministerio des negocioes estrangeiros, Lisbon (AMNE), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Archives Nationales, Section d'outre-mer, Paris (ANSOM), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Archives du Senegal, Dakar (AS), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Archivio storico del Ministero degli affari esteri, Rome (ASMAE), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Tuskegee Archives, Tuskegee Institute, Alabama (ATT), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Tuskegee Archives, Tuskegee Institute, Alabama (ATTa), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - British Museum, London, 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Centre des archives d'outre-mer, Aix-en-Provence, France (CAOM), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - University of Cape Town Library, Cape Town, South Africa (CSA), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Department of Archives, Black Rock, Barbados (DAB), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Archives of the Department evangelique francais d'action apostolique, Paris (DEFAP), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation, United States of America Department of Justice, Washington, D.C. (DJ-FBI), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Library of Congress, Washington, D.C. (DLC), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - National Archives, Washington, D.C. (DNA), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Pitts Theological Library, Emory University, Atlanta Georgia (GAPT), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - God's Kingdom Society Papers, Nigeria (GKSP), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Gambia Public Records Office, Banjul (GPRO), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - University of Ibadan Library, Ibadan, Nigeria (IU), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Jamaica Archives, Spanish Town, Jamaica (JA), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Killie Campbell African Library, University of Natal, Durban, South Africa (KCAL), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Kenya National Archives (KNA), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - League of Nations Archives, Geneva, 1996 (Box PA21)
    - University of Massachusetts Library, Amherst (MU), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - National Archives of Ghana, Regional Office, Cape Coast (NaGh), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - National Archives of Lesotho, Maseru (NAL), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - National Archives of Malawi, Zomba (NaMal), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - National Archives of Nigeria, Ibadan (NAN), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - National Archives of Nigeria, Emugu Branch (NAN-E), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - National Archives of Namibia, Windhoek (NaNam), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - National Archives of Zambia (NaZam), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - National Archives of Zimbabwe, Harare (NaZim), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - New York Supreme Court, Hall of Records, New York (NNHR), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Public Records Office (Pro), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Schomberg Center for Research in Black Culture, New York (NN-Sc), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - State Library, Salem, Oregon (Or), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Sierra Leone Public Archives Office, Fourah Bay College, Freetown (PAOSL), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - South African Government Archives, Pretoria (SAGA), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Cape Archives, Cape Town, South Africa (SAGA-CA), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Service des archives der Ministere des affaires etrangeres, Brussels (SAMAE), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - School of Oriental and African Studies Library, University of London (SOAS), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Tanzania National Archives (TNA), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - University of California, Los Angeles, Department of Special Collections (UCLA), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Vereinigte Evangelisch Mission (VEM), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Washington National Records Center, Suitland, Maryland (WNRC), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Western Reserve Historical Society, Cleveland, Ohio (WRHS), 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Letters received from archives granting permission and requesting volumes, 1996 (Box PA21)
    - Afro-American library inventory, 1986 (Box PA21)
    - Research manual and directions, 1982-1988 (Box PA21)
    - Research correspondence Vol. 6, 1985, 1986, 1988; 3 folders (Box PA21)
    - Forms to enclose in correspondence, undated (Box PA21)
    - Encyclopedia USA, Sports Encyclopedia, etc., 1986-1987 (Box PA21)
    - Research addresses - state historical societies, undated (Box PA21)
    - Union List of Newspapers, undated (Box PA21)
    - Research for Vol. 7, undated (Box PA21)
    - Olivier, Sydney - annotated work, 1930-1932 (Box PA21)
    - Hitler and Colonies, undated (Box PA21)
    - Map Library information, 1985 (Box PA21)
    - Miscellaneous research notes, 1985-1987 (Box PA21)
    - ASA Letters, 1993 (Box PA21)
    - Annotations, 1993 (Box PA21)
    - Editing, transcription guidelines and rules, 1990, 1992 (Box PA21)
    - Returned, renewed book slips, 1992-1993 (Box PA21)
    - CAASL works ordered, 1978-1979 (Box PA23)
    - Technical Advisory Committee, 1985 (Box PA23)
    - African Series, 1985 (Box PA23)
    - Lakroum, Dr. Monique, 1986 (Box PA23)
    - Celeste, Richard F., 1985 (Box PA23)
    - Hopkins, Dr. Anthony - University of Birmingham, 1985 (Box PA23)
    - African Series editorial arrangement, undated (Box PA23)
    - African Series, 1983-1985; 2 folders (Box PA23)
    - African Series contract - miscellaneous, 1985 (Box PA23)
    - African Series list of contributors, 1985 (Box PA23)
    - Hoenisch, Michael E., 1983-1985 (Box PA23)
    - Inventory of African Series correspondence, 1983 Oct-1984 Aug (Box PA23)
    - Mailing list, undated (Box PA23)
    - UC Press Vol. X, 1994, 1997 (Box PA23)
    - Article for NARA's Record, 1994, 1997 (Box PA23)
    - Permissions requests, 1997 (Box PA23)
    - MAPS African Series, Katya's File, 1997 (Box PA23)
    - Mapmakers, 1994 (Box PA23)
  - Grant Proposals and Documentation, 2
    The Grant Proposals and Documentation subseries includes funding applications and proposals, prepared reports, and required reporting documentation for institutions including NHPRC and NEH.
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH), 1973-1997 (Box PA6)
      Includes narratives, proposals, and summaries
    - National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC), 1998 (Box PA7)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH), 1985-2000 (Box PA8)
    - NHPRC progress report and renewal request, 1978-1979; 2 folders (Box PA9)
    - The Rockefeller Foundation - proposal for funding, 1979 (Box PA9)
    - NEH grant proposal, 1980 (Box PA9)
    - NEH renewal, 1980-1981 (Box PA9)
    - NHPRC progress report and renewal request, 1980 (Box PA9)
    - NHPRC consortium, 1980-1985 (Box PA9)
    - NHPRC progress report and renewal request, 1981-1982 (Box PA9)
    - Gifts and matching, 1981-1984 (Box PA9)
    - NEH renewal request, 1981-1984 (Box PA9)
    - NHPRC renewal request, 1982 Oct (Box PA9)
    - NHPRC renewal request, 1983 Sep (Box PA9)
    - GSA (Rockefeller Foundation) proposal, award, 1983 Dec-1984 Nov (Box PA9)
    - NEH renewal proposal, 1984 (Box PA9)
    - NHPRC editing fellow, 1984-1985 (Box PA9)
    - NHPRC renewal request, 1984 Sep (Box PA9)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. Project - Georgia, 1985 (Box PA9)
      used as research for Garvey Papers Project
    - NEH lobbying effort, 1985 (Box PA9)
    - NHPRC renewal request, 1985 Aug (Box PA9)
    - Chronicle of Higher Education Hill article, 1986 Mar 3 (Box PA9)
    - Hill, Robert - resume, 1987 (Box PA9)
    - Ahmanson Foundation, 1987 May (Box PA9)
    - GSA (Rockefeller Foundation) Award, 1986-1987 (Box PA9)
    - National Community Funds, 1987 Oct 1 (Box PA9)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities - MG and UNIA, 1985-1990 (Box PA19)
    - National Historical Publications and Records Commission - Caribbean Series, 2000 Oct (Box PA19)
    - NEH correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box PA19)
    - UCLA Foundation, 1985-1996 (Box PA19)
- Other Works (OW), 1911-2011 and undated; 5; 27 boxes
  Robert Hill's other edited publications are included in the Other Works series. Contracts, correspondence, facsimiles, drafts and research related to these projects are included in this series.
  - Edited by RAH, 1
    The Black Man: A Monthly Magazine of Negro Thought and Opinion was a magazine created and edited by Marcus Garvey beginning in 1938. Garvey printed many of his own speeches and writings in the magazine, and the periodical highlights the work and accomplishments of the UNIA. Robert Hill published a compilation of Black Man issues in his 1975 book of the same name. Related facsimiles, correspondence, and drafts are described at folder level.
    The Crusader was a magazine edited by Cyril V. Briggs. Like Marcus Garvey, Briggs immigrated to the U.S. from the Caribbean in the early 1900s. Briggs worked as a journalist for the New York Amsterdam News before starting The Crusader in 1918. A Garveyite turned Communist, Briggs founded the "African Blood Brotherhood" in 1919, an activist group that opposed imperialism and colonialism. Initially, The Crusader praised the accomplishments of Garvey and the UNIA, but Briggs later used it as a venue to attack Garvey, specifically targeting his Black Star Line and drawing attention to Garvey's arrest. Robert Hill published issues of The Crusader in his 1987 publication of the same name. Related facsimiles, correspondence, and drafts are described at folder level.
    The FBI's "Racial Conditions in the United States during World War II" (RACON) was an investigative effort conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) during World War II to monitor black radicalism and racial protests in various regions of the U.S. Beginning as a security review entitled, "Foreign-Inspired Agitation Among the American Negroes," which aimed to find the individuals responsible for encouraging black resistance and attempted to connect certain African American activists with spies, Communists, and foreign officials, it later morphed into a comprehensive look at racial conditions. Commissioned in June of 1942 and coming to a close the following August, RACON was created from individual reports supplied by all fifty-six field divisions of the FBI. As such, it highlights the many different struggles faced by African Americans during the war years and provides a look into their everyday efforts to contest discrimination. Hill published the report in its entirety in The FBI's Racon: Racial Conditions in the United States During World War II. The collection contains copies of RACON and other FBI records, some of which the FBI intended to discard but sent to Hill instead. Related facsimiles, correspondence, and drafts are described at folder level.
    George Samuel Schuyler (1895-1977) was an African American author and journalist published in The Crisis, Nation, Negro Digest, American Mercury, and National Review under multiple pen names from the 1920s to the 1960s. Schuyler's political views ranged from socialist in the 1920s to describing himself as an American patriot in the 1960s, who believed the Civil Rights Movement was a communist plot to destroy America. Robert Hill collected many of Schuyler's essays, short stories, and novellas. Two of Schuyler's novellas, "The Ethiopian Murder Mystery: A Story of Love and International Intrigue" and "Revolt in Ethiopia: A Tale of Black Insurrection Against Italian Imperialism," were republished in Hill's Ethiopian Stories. This series also includes Schuyler's unpublished short stories. Related facsimiles, correspondence, and drafts are described at folder level.
    Life and Lessons is a companion to The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers published by Hill in 1987. The book is a collection of autobiographical and other works written by Garvey, dating from the time of his imprisonment in 1923 to his death in 1940. Related facsimiles, correspondence, and drafts are described at folder level.
    Walter Anthony Rodney (1942–1980) was a Guyanese historian, political activist and scholar, who was assassinated in Guyana in 1980. Rodney and Robert Hill were friends and collaborators. The materials in this series are from Hill's research on Rodney to aid him in editing Walter Rodney Speaks: The Making of an African Intellectual, and writing the foreword for the volume. Related facsimiles, correspondence, and drafts are described at folder level.
    C.L.R. James (Cyril Lionel Robert James), 1901-1989 was a Trinidadian born, Marxist historian, writer, and founding member of the Pan-African movement. Robert Hill is also literary executor of the James' estate and General Editor of The C.L.R. James Archives at Duke University Press. Hill's research, writings, correspondence, and contracts relating to James are included and described at folder level.
    Robert Hill's Pan-African Biography is a collection of essays that were featured in a colloquium held in the spring of 1982 at the African Studies Center at the University of California, Los Angeles. Hill was the editor of the project, which was published in 1987. Related facsimiles, correspondence, and drafts are described at folder level.
    - RACON - FBI Foreign Inspired Agitation Among Negroes - New York Division, 1942 Jul-1949 Oct; 16 folders (Box OW1)
    - RACON - FBI Foreign Inspired Agitation Among Negroes - New York Division, African Nationalist Pioneer Movemement, 1942 Sep-1964 Dec (Box OW1)
    - RACON - FBI Foreign Inspired Agitation Among Negroes - Cincinnati Division, 1943 Mar-Dec (Box OW1)
    - RACON - FBI Survey of Racial Conditions manuscript, 1995 Jan 18 (Box OW1)
    - RACON - FBI Survey of Racial Conditions, 1942; 6 folders (Box OW1)
    - RACON - FBI Survey of Racial Conditions, letters and other documents, 1942-1943; 4 folders (Box OW1)
    - RACON - FBI Sedition Act, Gulam Bogans et al., 1940 Oct-1942 Sep; 2 folders (Box OW2)
    - RACON - FBI Allah Temple of Islam, 1940 Oct-1942 Aug; 2 folders (Box OW2)
    - RACON - FBI Ethiopian Pacifist Movement, 1941 Dec-1943 Jan; 5 folders (Box OW2)
    - RACON - FBI Racial Situation in US, 1944 Aug-1945 Jul; 3 folders (Box OW2)
    - RACON - FBI Racial Matters, 1947 Oct-1959 Jan (Box OW2)
    - RACON - FBI Christian Democrats, 1945 Jan 4 (Box OW2)
    - RACON - FBI Communist Party USA, Agitation Among Negroes, 1950-1952; 2 folders (Box OW2)
    - RACON - FBI miscellaneous files, 1935-1972 (Box OW2)
    - RACON - FBI newspaper clippings, 1938-1947; 5 folders (Box OW2)
    - RACON - Department of Justice Correspondence, non-Garvey, microfilm printouts, 1917 (Box OW3)
    - RACON - Department of Justice Correspondence, microfilm printouts, 1917-1919; 3 folders (Box OW3)
    - RACON - Department of Justice Correspondence, microfilm printouts, 1917-1919; 4 folders (Box OW4)
    - RACON - Department of Justice Correspondence, microfilm printouts, 1917-1919; 4 folders (Box OW5)
    - RACON - Department of Justice Correspondence, microfilm printouts, 1917-1919; 3 folders (Box OW6)
    - RACON - Frohlich, William - correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box OW7)
    - RACON - Strickland, Bill, 1973-1986 (Box OW7)
    - RACON - Sundkler, Bendt, 1974-1982 (Box OW7)
    - RACON - Walvin, James, 1981 (Box OW7)
    - RACON - Willan, Brian, 1978-1983 (Box OW7)
    - RACON - DAH, San Francisco, 1978-1980 (Box OW7)
    - RACON - GSA, diplomatic branch documents, 1934-1938 (Box OW7)
    - RACON - research requests, 1979-1980 (Box OW7)
    - RACON - Chadwick-Healey, Inc., 1980, 1986-1988 (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - Duse Mohamed Ali and American Genocide research facsimiles and transcriptions, 2004-2005 (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - correspondence by and about Duse Mohamed Ali, research facsimiles, 1995 (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - MacDermot, T.H. on Duse Mohamed Ali facsimiles, 1913 (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - census, periodical and newspaper references to Duse Mohamed Ali, facsimiles, 1901-1925 (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - introduction to Duse Mohamed Ali, book annotations, undated (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - Duse Mohamed Ali background research, 2009 (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - Duse Mohamed Ali autobiography, with Hill, Robert annotations, drafts, 2011 (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - correspondence regarding possible copyright infringement, Duse Mohamed Ali book facsimiles, 1911-1913 (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - research, 2009; 2 folders (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - Hill Celebrity Concerts letterhead, 1985 (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - I, Marcus Garvey review, 1991 Oct (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - biography of Dr. J Albert Thorne correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - biography of Theophilus E.S. Scholes correspondence, 1973-1979; 2 folders (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - Pacific Movement of the Eastern World correspondence, 1973-1983; 5 folders (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - W.E.B. DuBois, Pan-African Congress correspondence, 1971-1982; 2 folders (Box OW7)
    - Pan-African Biography - British Museum, Victoria and Albert Museum, 1979-1982 (Box OW7)
    - George Schuyler - newspaper articles about, 1936-1938, 1977 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - miscellaneous, 1937, 1990 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - bibliography, personal papers, indexes - Schomburg Papers, 1990 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - correspondence to / from P.L. Prattis - Howard Xeroxes, 1957-1960 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - correspondence and miscellaneous articles - later years, 1962-1969 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - correspondence and miscellaneous articles - Schomburg Papers, 1924-1939 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - letters, most from red scrapbook, 1923-1931 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - letters, 1937-1940; 2 folders (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - Brooks, Samuel I. - Marcus Garvey: An Analysis, 1929-1990 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - miscellaneous articles in Pittsburg Courier and Stories, 1928-1930 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - re: Garvey, 1929-1933 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - articles by P.L. Prattis, 1936 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - miscellaneous articles by J.A. Rogers, 1936 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - J.A. Rogers on Marcus Garvey, undated (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - notes on related literature, 1920-1953 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - DuBois, W.E.B., 1927-1932 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - Stapledon, Olaf, 1991 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - articles - Schomburg Papers, 1932 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - American Mercury, etc., articles, 1932-1945 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - articles in Views and Reviews column, 1930-1936 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - articles on communism - by and about, 1933-1939, 1968 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - Views and Reviews, 1934-1937; 3 folders (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - Liberia articles, 1933 (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - Ideas for articles and plays on race - box of ideas, undated (Box OW8)
    - George Schuyler - articles collected - box of ideas, undated (Box OW8)